<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resume first-name="Arindam" middle-name="" last-name="Nath">
	<!-- Profile detials -->
    <profile>
        <profile-detail name="About Me">
            <item-details>Experienced in mobile application development and underlying concepts of mobile software architecture and user interface design. Developing enterprise applications and frameworks.</item-details>
			<item-details>I have also handled pre sales activity, where my role was to communicate with the client about company's technical capabilities and project's technical documentation.</item-details>
			<item-details>Have worked on local as well as remote server databases for mobile devices. Experienced in developing mobile web application using MVC 4 architecture and HTML 5.</item-details>
			<item-details>Knowledge about game development technologies and production pipeline and in-depth idea about game designing and gameplay mechanics. Experience in OpenGL ES and 3D programming.</item-details>
			<item-details>Can work with graphic designing software like Adobe Photoshop and Autodesk Maya. Knowledge about color theory and typography which were/are actively implemented on all architected software.</item-details>
		</profile-detail>
        <profile-detail name="Education">
			<item-details>B.A. Hons. in Digital Media for Game Development from Prifysgol Cymru, Aberystwyth, Wales. Studies focused on game development, IT project management, multimedia design, technical planning, and business case analysis. Created working prototypes for games on numerous gaming platforms.</item-details>
		</profile-detail>
		<profile-detail name="Skills">
			<item-details>Mobile Software Architecture Planning</item-details>
			<item-details>Mobile Software Solutions Consulting</item-details>
			<item-details>Handling pre sales activities</item-details>
			<item-details>Android Development</item-details>
			<item-details>iPhone Development</item-details>
			<item-details>Windows Phone Development</item-details>
			<item-details>Mobile Web Application development using HTML 5</item-details>
			<item-details>Database Architecture</item-details>
			<item-details>Game Development</item-details>
			<item-details>UI Design</item-details>
		</profile-detail>
		<profile-detail name="Achievements">
			<item-details>"It's Just a Thought" won the award of Best Original Idea at the International Video Game Festival hoPlay '11 held in Spain.</item-details>
			<item-details>Discover India was awarded category winner award in a completion held by Appbazar.</item-details>
		</profile-detail>
    </profile>
	<!-- Work Exp detials -->
	<work-exp>
		<work-detial name="Source HOV" period="April 2012 – Present">Involved in developing software solutions for Android OS. Also play an active part in providing assistance to the product manager in conception of idea, technical/architectural documentation and implementation.</work-detial>
		<work-detial name="Congruent Infotech" period="April 2011 – April 2012">Working on multiple mobile platforms and mobile web applications development. Training freshers and experienced people about mobile technologies. Involved in handling company's first product Xpense Manager for multiple platforms which also included architecture of the application. Worked on various enterprise level off-shore projects with companies like 3M, Premera, Salford, Saksoft etc.</work-detial>
		<work-detial name="Black Pearl Infotech" period="October 2010 – March 2011">Lead developer and architect for games and applications on Apple iPhone /iPad and Android Handsets. Management of a team engaged in development of applications for Apple iPhone/ iPad and Android Handsets. Have also worked as a Project Manager on 2 projects and was a part of fresher training team.</work-detial>
		<work-detial name="Love Handle Developers" period="September 2010 – October 2010">Lead consultant for games on Apple iPhone and iPad. Management of a team engaged in development of applications for Apple iPhone and iPad. Design Consultant for in-house game productions.</work-detial>
		<work-detial name="Yellow Monkey Studios Pvt. Ltd." period="February 2010 – April 2010">As a mobile game developer worked on the game "It's just a thought". Create a 2D game engine for Android Handsets. Research on implementation of mobile phone cameras as a method of input in games.</work-detial>
		<work-detial name="Freelancer" period="October 2010 – July 2011">Was involved as a freelancer for developing applications on various mobile platforms.</work-detial>
		<work-detial name="Touch Me Not Apps (Indie)" period="October 2011 – Present">Working on android applications and games. More detials can be found on my blog touchmenotapps.tumblr.com</work-detial>
	</work-exp>
	<!-- Projects detials -->
	<projects>
	    <company name="Source HOV">
	        <projects-details name="SHOV Reader">SHOV Reader is an ebook reader which displays html data content along with the native OS UI to make it more user interactive. It has options to play video, view images, bookmarks, search content specific to the chapter.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Mobi QUB">Mobi QUB helps key decision makers of a company by accessing important enterprise data, to user with access clearances via there mobile devices.</projects-details>
	    </company>
	    <company name="Congruent Infotech">
	        <projects-details name="Xpense Manager">Xpense Manager is an expense manager application for android devices. The application is currently available at Android Market.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Vehicle Value Evaluator">An iPhone vehicle value evaluator for used cars. It is available at App Store.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Cobra">An education portal where students can log in using active directory credentials and view collage related datas like assignments, events etc.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="POCs">Worked on multiple POCs for various international clients, on areas like creating high level user interface and usability implementation for pre-sales demonstrations.</projects-details>
	    </company>
	    <company name="Black Pearl Infotech">
	        <projects-details name="VOAPK">Vopak is an enterprise application for the company Vopak. Was involved in building the whole android software architecture and acted Project Manager for this project.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="HanDy Calc">HanDy Calc was developed during fresher training program. It is available in Android Market.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Accelerando">Accelerando was a 1 day project. Was involved in building the whole application. It is available in Android Market.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="eFireTrack">eFireTrack is another enterprise application being developed by me and my team. Was involved for architecting the software and high level features coding.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Blue Penguin">Developing an educational game prototype for the company Blue Penguin. Was involved as a game logic programmer. The game was developed in Unreal Engine for PC.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Comic Book Application">Project involved in developing a comic book reader application. Was involved in, software architecture, user interface design and encryption.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Personal Dietitian">Was involved as software architect, acting project manager as well as a consultant to the sales department.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Zork for Kindle">Porting old text based game Zork, to Kindle devices.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Discover India">Developed an application that featured details about different places of tourist interest in India. This application was an entrant and category winner at Indian Android Developers Contest. It is available in the Android App Market.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Quick Mail">Developed an application that featured mail server configuration, email templates and 3D user interface. It is available in the Android App Market.</projects-details>
	    </company>
	    <company name="Love Handle Developers">
	        <projects-details name="Double Holdem">Development of Double Holdem, for iPhone. The game featured upto 9 AI poker players.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Projects from ABCMouse and Dr Laura Advice">Overseeing a team of 3 that involved on various applications for ABCMouse.com. Also acted as the technical advisor for the entire team.</projects-details>
	    </company>
	    <company name="Yellow Monkey Studios">
	        <projects-details name="Its Just a Thought">Was involved in conceptualizing the entire project and was a part of the development team. Also prototyped a game engine on android platform to port the game from iOS to Android. This game is available at iStore.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Research on input devices for modern Handsets">Was involved in developing a prototype, which used the phone’s camera input as a tool for game world interaction.</projects-details>
	    </company>
	    <company name="Freelancer">
	        <projects-details name="Proteus">Developed a media player application for android handsets and desktop. The application featured real-time decryption of the songs played by the media player.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Point Me">Point Me is an application that features reverse geo coding to get the exact street level address of the user. It also stores this data in a remote server so that it can be viewed by a second person. This feature allows company administrators to track their employees.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Cocina Mexicana">This application featured a list of different Mexican recipes. The application is currently available in the Apple Store.</projects-details>
	    </company>
	    <company name="TouchMeNot Apps">
	        <projects-details name="Memorabilia">Memorabilia is an android application that helps anyone store memorable event of their life as text, pictures, videos, audio and map tags. The user can later on view all these data specific to memeories. it is currently under development.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Radial Menu">Radial Menu is a UI compnent that is inspire by the Android webview menu item.</projects-details>
	        <projects-details name="Graph3r">Graph3r is a free to use android library for plotting various graphs. It is still under development.</projects-details>
	    </company>
	</projects>
	<!-- Interests detials -->
	<interests>
		<interests-details name="photography">http://www.flickr.com/photos/arindam_nath/</interests-details>
		<interests-details name="blogging">http://strider2023.tumblr.com/</interests-details>
		<interests-details name="game dev"></interests-details>
		<interests-details name="drawing"></interests-details>
		<interests-details name="cooking"></interests-details>
		<interests-details name="power-building"></interests-details>
		<interests-details name="swimming"></interests-details>
	</interests>
	<!-- Contact detials -->
	<contact>
		<address>33/15 G.V. House, Abith Nagar, Near Choolimedu Police Station, Choolimedu, Chennai - 94</address>
		<phone>+919884312488</phone>
		<phone>+918144071847</phone>
		<mail>strider2023@gmail.com</mail>
		<mail>arindamnath_1989@rediffmail.com</mail>
	</contact>
</resume>